Just one place... just one place...
tatta hitotsu tatta hitotsu no...
Just one of me... just one of me...
tatta hitori tatta hitori no...
I'm right here.
watashi wa koko
With a chest made of rubble, I can't even breathe.
gareki no mune iki mo dekinai
The rain starts to fall, like a slumbering cry.
furidasu ame nemuru you ni cry
What flower should I decorate myself with
kono sekai o ikinuku no naraba
To stay alive in this world?
donna hana o kazareba ii no?
I want to believe, but still can't manage it...
shinjitai kuse ni shinjirarezu ni
My powerless and pointless self
muryoku de muimi na jibun ga
Still embraces my heart.
soredemo kokoro de idakun da
I can hear a voice calling to me, saying, "Come this way!"
"kocchi e oide" to koe ga kikoeru
A limitless and reckless tomorrow
mugen de mubou na ashita ga
Will still be waiting for me somewhere.
soredemo dokoka de matsu kara
Just one place... just one place...
tatta hitotsu tatta hitotsu no...
Just one of me... just one of me...
tatta hitori tatta hitori no...
I'm right here.
watashi wa koko
I can hear cats meowing.
（チセ）
猫の鳴く声がする
Say, you cats have nine lives, do you not?
（ミナ）ねえ お前
猫の命は９つもあるんでしょう？
そんなに たくさんあるのなら
Since you have so many, why not spare one for me?
１つくらい
私にくれてもいいんじゃないかしら
Are you awake?
（エリアス）起きたかい？
Morning, Chise.
（エリアス）おはよう チセ
おっ… おはようございます
G-Good morning, sir.
You gave me a shock.
（エリアス）驚いたよ
One moment you collapsed,
the next, you'd fallen asleep.
いきなり倒れたと思ったら
すぐに眠ってしまったから
す… すみません
S-Sorry.
Was I that tired?
（チセ）
そんなに疲れてたかな
あの… ここは？
Uh, where are we?
（エリアス）
次のハニームーン先に向かう
列車だよ
It's the train to our next honeymoon destination.
Come in.
（エリアス）どうぞ
（車掌）
使いの方が お見えになってます
There is a messenger here to see you.
Bring them in.
（エリアス）通してもいいよ
This train is not meant for humans.
（エリアス）
この列車は人間用じゃないのさ
A cat?
（チセ）
猫？
Pleased to meet you, sir mage.
（ジャスパー）
お初に お目もじいたします
魔法使い殿
Word travels fast.
（エリアス）うわさが早いな
Rumors spread a hundred miles a day in the cat world.
（ジャスパー）
猫のうわさは 一日で
100マイルを さまよいますので
（チセ）しゃべった…
He spoke.
Perhaps that would be surprising
for a cat on its first or second life,
（ジャスパー）
１つ目や ３つ目なら いざ知らず
but this is my seventh.
私などは ７つ目ですから
There would be something wrong with me if I couldn't.
しゃべれないほうが
どうかしてます
First? Seventh?
（チセ）ひとつめに… ななつめ？
Haven't you heard?
（エリアス）
聞いたことはないかい？
猫には９つの命があるってね
Cats have nine lives.
Nine lives?
９つの命…
（ジャスパー）そのとおり
Exactly.
We cats become wiser with each life.
我ら猫は
命を経るごとに賢くなります
We too have the idea of "countries" and "kings."
国を理解し 我らの王を掲げるほど
我らが猫の王が
ウルタールにて お待ちです
Our King of Cats awaits at Ulthar, sir mage.
魔法使い殿
There are a lot of cats here.
猫が多いね
That's why it's the Kingdom of Cats.
（ジャスパー）
ですから 猫の国なのです
Here, there have historically been many cat lovers
昔から猫好きが多くて
邪険にする者もおりませんから
自然に
and none who are cruel to us,
so naturally, our numbers grew.
There are some other reasons as well, though.
まあ
それ以外に理由もあるのですが…
Barney! Where the heck have you been?
バーニー！
お前 今まで
どこを ほっつき歩いていたのだ！
The King wanted me to take
a look, so I was on patrol, Jasper.
（バーニー）
王が様子を見てこいっていうから
見回りしてたんだよ ジャスパー
You have a scent that takes me back.
おめえ 懐かしいにおいがすんな
昔 よくいた魔法使いたちと似た
におい…
You smell kind of like the
mages that I used to see around.
ニャー！
（エリアス）口が軽いケダモノだな
What an overly chatty animal.
何でえ！
Shut it, you prickly Thorn Mage.
とげとげしいな 茨(いばら)の魔法使い
I'm not going to scratch up your bride, so don't worry.
心配しなくても
嫁っこに爪なんざ立てやしねえよ
Even cats know about this?
猫にまで知られてるの…
Cats' rumors can easily make
it to the other side of the world.
猫のうわさは
地球の裏にだって届くのさ
She just looked at me.
（チセ）
今… こっちを見てた？
そういえば 王様は どこにいるの？
Oh, yeah. Where's this King?
あなたの すぐ隣に
Right next to you.
（モリィ）こんにちは 魔法使い
Hello, mage and apprentice.
そして お弟子さん
あなたが猫の… 王様
You're the King of Cats?
Yes.
ええ 私はモリィと申します
My name is Molly.
You must be Chise.
あなたがチセですね
You struck me as odd,
choosing to pair bond with this cranky man.
この偏屈な方と
つがいになるなんて
物好きな方と思っておりましたの
（エリアス）うるさいよ
Shut up.
（チセ）
つがい…
Pair bond...
（モリィ）
２人とも
よく いらっしゃいましたね
I'm glad to see you both here.
I don't know what I would have
done if they'd sent a sorcerer instead.
魔術師が よこされたら
どうしようかと思いましたわ
Would it have been bad if we were sorcerers?
魔術師だとダメなんですか？
俺らは魔術師が嫌いなんだよ
嬢ちゃん！
We hate sorcerers, lady!
ヤツらは狡猾(こうかつ)で卑しい無法者だ
They're skeevy, lawless lowlifes!
好んで近づきたくないね
I don't wanna be anywhere near them.
あなた方が教会から言われて
来たのは分かっています
I know you were sent here by the Church.
我らの地に障りはないと
言いたいところですが…
I wish I could tell you that there
was nothing wrong with our land.
However, we're in a bit of trouble.
少々 困ったことが起きています
手を貸していただけるのでしょう？
魔法使い
You'll help us, right, mage?
That's why I'm here, although I wish I weren't.
（エリアス）
そのために来たんだよ
不本意ながらね
Hey, who are you, miss?
（アリー）お姉ちゃん 誰？
あっ エ… エリア…
E-Elias...
Who were you talking to outside my house?
（アリー）
うちの前で立ち止まって
誰と お話ししてたの？
Oh, no. I just noticed the cute cat on the wall.
あっ いや…
かわいい猫が壁にいるなって
That's our cat.
（アリー）その子 うちの子なの！
とってもきれいでしょ？
Isn't she pretty?
Molly, it'll be time to eat soon.
モリィ もうすぐ ご飯だから
早く おうちに入るのよ
Come inside, okay?
My owner.
飼い主ですわ
生まれたときから見てますから
娘のようなものですの
I've looked after her since she
was born, so she's like my child.
She's a cute girl.
かわいい子だね
自慢の娘ですわ
I'm proud of her like she's my own daughter.
あ… エリアス
Elias.
I hate kids.
（エリアス）子供は嫌いなんだよ
They don't even have magic,
魔力もないのに
本質を見る力だけは強いもんだから
but they have a strong ability
to perceive the essence of a being.
Sometimes, they can see through me.
見破られるときがあるんだよ
I might as well go investigate.
ちょうどいい
このまま ちょっと調べてくる
（チセ）
えっ？ どこへ行くんですか？
Where are you going?
（エリアス）
どうも嫌な気配がするんだ
Something doesn't feel right.
Well, then, I'd like to show you around.
（モリィ）
では
あなただけでも ご案内しますわ
Long ago—so long ago that even we,
with our nine lives, don't have many tales to tell of it—
（モリィ）遠い昔…
９つの命を持つ我々さえも
語り継げないほど遠い昔
there was a man here who enjoyed killing us.
この地には 我々を殺すことを
楽しむ者がいました
Killing cats?
猫たちを…
Run as we may, hide as we may,
どんなに隠れても
どんなに逃げても
we were captured, and our lives were snuffed out.
我々は捕らえられ
その命は すり潰されていった
It was the first King of Cats who ended that.
それを終わらせたのが
はじめの猫の王です
The first king gathered the remaining
cats, and together they attacked.
はじめの王は
残された猫たちと共に
その者を襲いました
They clawed him apart,
chewed him to bits, drank his blood,
かみ砕き かじり裂き 飲みすすり
and left not even a trace of him.
かけらも残さず平らげて
Each generation of kings pays for
the reverence we receive by sacrificing
崇敬を受ける代わりに
いくつもの命を使って
永久に澱(よど)みを縫い止めるのが
several of our lives in order
to hold the corruption at bay.
That's the price we pay for our veneration.
代々の猫の王の役目です
Look really carefully.
目を凝らして見てみるんだ
嬢ちゃんなら見えるだろ
I'm sure you can see it.
It's filth.
あれは穢(けが)れ
The corrupt state of souls that were never cleansed...
浄化されない
魂の澱みです
The corruption has been trying to escape in recent days.
最近になって
あの澱みが出てこようと
してるのです
It seeks maniacally and indiscriminately
to take the lives of both cats and humans.
猫であろうが
ヒトであろうが
関係なく妄執によって
命を奪わんとするモノ…
I must not allow it to emerge,
あれが
出てくることだけは
防がなければ…
even if it kills me.
私が死んでも
For the girl's sake?
（チセ）
あの子が いるから？
What mother fails to protect her own child?
（モリィ）
己の子を守らない母が
いるでしょうか？
It would be unthinkable, at least to me.
少なくとも 私には
考えられないことですわ
Yeah. I guess.
（チセ）そう… だね
Chise!
（モリィ）チセ！
Don't take this personally.
（アリス）悪く思わないでくれよ
Mina.
（マシュー）ミナ… ミナ…
（ドアが開く音）
（マシュー）ミナ
Mina.
Matthew.
マシュー
I'm home, Mina.
（マシュー）ただいま ミナ
まだ寝ていたほうが
いいんじゃないのか？
Shouldn't you be in bed?
大丈夫よ マシュー
I'm fine, Matthew.
（マシュー）はい
Here.
（ミナ）まあ！
Wow!
There were lots of them blooming by the garden.
畑の近くに たくさん咲いててさ
I wanted to show you.
君に見せたくて
Thank you.
ありがとう
How's your fever?
（マシュー）熱は？
You're still burning up.
まだ高いじゃないか
Come on.
（マシュー）ほら
Shoo.
Get off your butt and go catch some mice or something.
ぐうたらしてないで
ネズミでも捕ってこい
あっ… なんだよ もう
What's his problem?
本当に ミナ以外には
懐かないんだからな
That cat seriously only likes you.
I heard there's a wandering sorcerer in town right now.
今 町のほうに
流しの魔術師が来ているらしいんだ
I'll ask if they have any good medicine.
いい薬でもないか
少し話を聞いてくるよ
I'm sorry, dear.
（ミナ）ごめんなさい あなた
I always do this to you.
いつも いつも…
You don't need to apologize.
（マシュー）謝ることなんてないさ
You've always been prone to sickness,
but I knew that when we got together.
確かに
君は昔から体を壊しやすいけど
承知で 一緒になったんだから
Now, get some sleep.
さあ ちゃんと寝てるんだよ
You better not be knitting socks or coats like last time.
この間みたいに 靴下だの 上着だの
編んでたらダメだからね
Fine.
（ミナ）は〜い
See you soon.
いってらっしゃい
ハア…
本当に… 猫みたいに
命が９つあればよかったのに
If only I had nine lives, like a cat.
This was my sin,
（ミナ）これは私の罪
あの人がくれる愛の上に
あぐらをかいてしまった罰
and my punishment for resting my laurels on his love.
あなたは…
Who are you?
I suppose you could say I'm the core of this corruption.
（ミナ）
この澱みの核…
とでもいうのかしら
（チセ）核？
Core?
この人は
私にしがみついて離れない
This man is affixed to me. He won't let go.
It's my fault that he's become such an abomination.
私のせいで この人は
こんなにも醜いモノに
成り果ててしまった
（チセ）この人？
This man...
（ミナ）マシュー
Matthew.
My husband.
私の夫
Please.
お願い
For his sake,
この人を… 私を…
and mine...
（チセ）
待って　私は まだ何も知らない…
Wait, I don't know anything yet—
（エリアス）
チセ…
Chise.
Chise!
チセ！
Chise.
チセ…
Elias.
エリアス…
I'm sorry I didn't come sooner.
（エリアス）遅れて ごめんね
ゲホッ…
Are you all right?
（エリアス）
大丈夫？ 息できてる？
Can you breathe?
Yes.
（チセ）はい…
What happened to the one
who threw Chise into the pond?
（エリアス）
チセを池に落としたヤツは？
（バーニー）
ピカッと光って
消えちまったんだよ！
She gave off a flash and vanished.
（エリアス）
あちこちに魔力の残滓(ざんし)があった
There was magic residue all over the place.
It looks like someone's trying to get in our way.
どうやら 誰かさんが
僕らの邪魔をしているみたいだ
I'd like to give you time to rest,
ゆっくり
休ませてあげたいところなんだけど
チセ
君にやってもらうことができた
but Chise, I have a task for you.
For me?
私に？
We need to do something about that, soon.
（エリアス）
あれを早急に
どうにかしないといけない
I want you to cleanse it.
君に浄化してほしいんだ
封じることはできても
それは問題を先延ばしにするだけだ
Containing it only delays the inevitable problem.
We don't need the magic to
contain it, but magic to cleanse it.
必要なのは封じる魔法ではなく
浄化する魔法
浄化する魔法…
Magic to cleanse it?
I haven't had you practice magic properly yet.
（エリアス）
まだ君に きちんと
魔法を扱わせたことはないけれど…
But I believe you can do it.
君なら やれると思う
If I can't, will he lose faith in me?
（チセ）
もし できなかったら
幻滅されるだろうか
If you think I can,
（チセ）
エリアスが できるって言うのなら
やります
I'll do it.
You heard her, King of Cats.
（エリアス）
そういうことだ 猫の王
分かりました
Understood.
できうるかぎりの人払いは
しておきましょう
I'll clear the place of as many people as I can.
I'm counting on you two.
お願いしますよ
あなたたち
Yes, ma'am.
（２匹）イエス マム！
At night, then, when there aren't any people.
（エリアス）
じゃあ 人気(ひとけ)のない夜に
This is a mantle purified with snowmelt.
（エリアス）
これは 雪解け水で清めた外套(がいとう)
We use frankincense in the censer.
光香炉(こうこうろ)には乳香ね
Let's use a branch of gorse in place of a staff.
杖(つえ)には
ハリエニシダを代用品にしよう
You would normally need your own chant and staff.
本来なら
自分の呪文と杖が必要なんだけれど
But we'll have to make do.
今回は しかたない
Is your lecture going to take a while?
（エアリエル）
その話って長くなるのン？
An ariel.
（チセ）エアリエル！
久しぶりね チ〜セ
It's been a while, Chise.
They'll be a great help for our task today.
（エリアス）
今回の役には うってつけだからね
この間のこともあるし
本当は嫌だけど
Although I don't look forward to it,
especially after what happened.
浄化するなり
消滅させるなりするんなら
Cleansing and extinguishing is what we're good at.
アタシたちが向いてるものン
The wind clears away everything.
風は ぜ〜んぶ消してしまうわン
肉も骨も 木々や岩さえも
風化させちゃう
Meat, bone, even trees and boulders.
We weather it all away.
So we're the best ones for the job.
だから 今回のことは
アタシたちが テキニンってわけ
そういえば…
Speaking of which, why is it me and not you?
なんで エリアスじゃなくて
私なんですか？
（エリアス）
ああ… 情けないけど
僕は この手の魔法は苦手なんだ
I hate to admit it, but I'm not good at this kind of magic.
My essence is shadow, after all.
僕の本性は影だからさ
I'm not compatible.
相性が悪いんだよ
It's all right, Chise.
大丈夫だよ チセ
All you have to do is picture it in your mind.
君は 心の中で思い描くだけでいい
Just wish for it to disappear, like a spring wind
春先の強い風で 冷たい冬の全てが
吹き飛ばされていくように
blowing away the cold winter.
あれが消えることを願えばいい
The ariels will guide you from there.
そうすれば
エアリエルが導いてくれる
はい
Okay.
Chise, love the world.
（エリアス）
チセ 世界を愛するんだ
The world you lived in may not have been your ally.
君のいる世界は
君の味方じゃなかったかもしれない
But it wasn't your enemy, either.
でも 敵ではない
Your key is already in the silver lock.
君の鍵は
もう銀の錠に差し込まれている
All that's left to do is to open it.
あとは開けるだけさ
Then again, that's just
something someone once told me.
（エリアス）
まあ これは
知人の受け売りなんだけどね
Do you love this place, Elias?
（チセ）
エリアスは ここを愛してますか？
Sure.
（エリアス）そうだね
Will he lose faith in me if I fail?
（チセ）
もし できなかったら
幻滅されるだろうか
でも…
But...
（ミナ）この人を… 私を…
For his sake, and mine, kill us.
殺して
How could she say that with such a calm voice?
（チセ）
あんなに静かな声で
なぜ あの人は
あんなことを言ったんだろう
How did they end up the way they did?
なぜ あの２人は
あんなになってしまったんだろう
Don't worry.
（エアリエル）
大丈夫よン 落ち着いて
Stay calm.
Do I have to wipe them out?
消す… しかないのかな
（エアリエル）チセ！
動かないでくれると助かる
I'd appreciate it if you wouldn't move.
You're from earlier.
（チセ）昼間の…
Ariel!
（チセ）エアリエル！
Sorry, we have a use for that thing.
（レンフレッド）すまないね
それには利用価値があるのでね
We can't let you get rid of it.
消されると困るんだ
（２匹）シャーッ！
No wonder I smelled something unfamiliar.
（エリアス）
どうりで
嗅ぎ慣れない においだったわけだ
Renfred.
レンフレッド
I'm surprised you remember my name.
（レンフレッド）
お前が俺の名前を覚えていたとはな
It looks like you take good care of her.
随分 目をかけているみたいだな
Is it because she's your precious
test subject, Pilum Murialis?
やはり
彼女が大事な実験体だからか？
裂き喰らう城(ピルム･ムーリアリス)
Test subject?
実験体…
チセ！ こいつの言うことなんて
Chise! Don't listen to him!
聞いちゃダメ…
お前たちの嫌いな
鉄の糸で編まれた手袋だ
This glove is made of iron fibers,
which you hate so much.
（レンフレッド）動くと傷つく
（エアリエル）うう…
Squirm, and you'll get hurt.
Ariel!
エアリエル！
魔法使いが なんで そんなこと！
Why would a mage do such a thing?
Mage?
（レンフレッド）魔法使い？
You're mistaken.
勘違いをしているようだが
私は魔術師でね
I'm a sorcerer.
Poor girl.
かわいそうに
妖精にまで だまされているのか
Even the fairies are deceiving you.
（チセ）だます？
Deceiving me?
She isn't deceiving you.
（エリアス）だましてなんかいない
We detest lies.
僕らは うそを好まない
Indeed.
（レンフレッド）
そうだな
お前たちは真実を黙するだけだ
All you do is conceal the truth.
That's how you put this unfortunate child on a leash,
そうやって 哀れな子供を
己の好奇心のためだけに
to try to use her to satisfy your own curiosity.
首輪でつないで
利用しようとしている
Why don't you tell her of the
fate that awaits a Sleigh Beggy?
彼女に伝えたらどうだ？
夜の愛し仔(スレイ･ベガ)の末路を
遠からず訪れる
その死を
Of the death that will soon come to her?
Death?
（チセ）死ぬ？
My death?
私が？
To keep the seeds I tie to this branch
eda ni musubu mi ga jukusu mae ni
From falling before they ripen
ochite shimawanu you
I bloom again in profusion, painfully
kurushii hodo ni mata sakimidareru
To connect myself to tomorrow.
asa e tsunagu you
Even as they're born again
nando kurikaeshi
And again,
kurikaeshi umaretemo
I'll always show them
itsumo atarashii
A brand new sky.
sora o misete ageyou
I'll pen a story that no one,
daremo mada daremo
No one has ever written.
kaitenai monogatari
On a map so white, pure white,
shiroi masshiroi
I'll draw it out, singing it aloud.
chizu ni kaite utaou
The girl's heart is rocked by the
truth with which she is confronted.
（チセ）
突きつけられた真実に
少女の心は揺れる
Will the despairing child's decision
行き場なき少女の選択は
猫の国に沈む悲しい妄執に
福音をもたらすのか
bring an end to the tragic obsession
lurking deep in the Kingdom of Cats?
中を見ちゃ… いけない！
You mustn't look inside!